Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/suhassuresha (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Time-Series Prediction Generative Modeling MLOps

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Kannada (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Limited Working)
Tamil (Limited Working)

Honors-Awards

Schlumberger Innovation Fellow

Publications

Nonlinear dynamics and intermittency in a turbulent reacting wake with density ratio as bifurcation parameter

Capturing Uncertainty And Preserving Geological Realism with Attentive Neural Processes for Subsurface Property Modeling

Automated staging of knee osteoarthritis severity using deep neural networks

Probabilistic Semantic Inpainting with Pixel Constrained CNNs

Patents

System and method for identifying subsurface structures

Super resolution machine learning model for seismic visualization generation

Rig state detection using video data

Generalizable machine learning algorithms for flash calculations

Suhas Suresha

Machine Learning Engineer

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

I am a machine learning scientist with 7+ years of work experience. I have worked on several ML projects in the fields of computer vision, natural language processing, time-series prediction, and generative modeling. Additionally, I have experience in machine learning operations (MLOps), having built and deployed production-grade ML models and pipelines. I also have experience in cloud backend and iOS app development.

Experience

Adobe

Senior Machine Learning Engineer October 2024 - Present (3 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Forward

Engineer

February 2023 - June 2024 (1 year 5 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Worked on a mission to get the world's best healthcare to a billion people for free.

QALY

Co-Founder and Head of ML

November 2020 - December 2022 (2 years 2 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

The QALY app helps people get their ECGs reviewed for abnormal rhythms within minutes. As head of ML at QALY:

- 1. Trained ML models on ECG time-series data to automatically detect abnormal rhythms and annotate relevant beats.
- 2. Deployed the ML models to production using cloud services. These models were deployed live and provided real-time insights within the QALY app.
- 3. Built the iOS app that has been downloaded by more than 50,000 people on the App Store.

4. Deployed multiple backend services using cloud tools.

Schlumberger

3 years 3 months

Senior Data Scientist

January 2020 - October 2020 (10 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- 1. Implemented deep generative modeling algorithms to model realistic geological properties conditioned on physical measurement.
- 2. Worked on deep learning super-resolution algorithms to reconstruct highresolution seismic data from low-resolution input. This helped reduce storage and communication costs associated with generating seismic visualizations.
- 3. Worked on ML algorithms applied to reservoir simulations.

Data Scientist

August 2017 - January 2020 (2 years 6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- 1. Applied 3D fully convolutional deep learning algorithms to segment relevant geological structures from seismic data
- 2. Implemented natural language processing algorithms to extract relevant information from unstructured text reports.
- 3. Worked on a new semantic inpainting algorithm using Pixel Constrained CNNs.

Stanford University
Graduate Research Assistant
September 2016 - June 2017 (10 months)

United States

I was a graduate research assistant in the Mobilize lab (http://mobilize.stanford.edu/) under Prof. Scott Delp. I worked on quantifying radiographic knee osteoarthritis severity using deep learning models.

Schlumberger
Data Science Intern
June 2016 - September 2016 (4 months)

Worked on time-series alignment and deep learning algorithms to solve problems in automation.

Indian Institute of Science Research Intern May 2013 - July 2013 (3 months) Evaluated performance of Eigen value solvers for Parabolized Stability Equation (PSE)

involving sparse matrices and optimized existing FORTRAN code-base to reduce

execution time. Modeled nonparallel and nonlinear effects observed in the aeroacoustics of a jet engine.

Education

Stanford University

Master of Science (M.S.), Computational and Applied Mathematics · (2015 - 2017)

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

M.Tech and B.Tech (Honours) in Aerospace Engineering · (2010 - 2015)